dicksmith.co.nz 2019-12-22

# Dick Smith | Privacy Policy

## 1\. Openness and transparency

Online Business Number 1 Pty Ltd trading as Dick Smith Group and its related bodies corporate (Dick Smith Group) is committed to protecting your privacy and respects and upholds your rights under the Australian Privacy Principles (APPs) contained in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) ("Privacy Act"). By using this website, you agree to and consent to the collection, use, holding and disclosure of personal information by Dick Smith Group as set out in this policy.

## 2\. Personal information

Personal information is information or an opinion about an individual whose identity is apparent, or can be reasonably ascertained, from that information or opinion. Personal information we may collect from you includes, without limitation, your name, address, email address, telephone number(s) and date of birth.

## 3\. Collection

Dick Smith Group will collect personal information only by lawful and fair means and not in an unreasonably intrusive way. If it is reasonable and practical to do so, Dick Smith Group will only collect personal information about you directly from you. Dick Smith Group may collect your personal information from reputable third party lead generation sources for marketing purposes, but only where you have consented to the disclosure of your information to Dick Smith Group and for Dick Smith Group to send you marketing communications. Dick Smith Group will not collect personal information unless the information is reasonably necessary for our functions and activities.

If you use a pseudonym when dealing with us or you do not provide identifiable information Dick Smith Group may not be able to provide you with any or all of our services as requested. If you wish to remain anonymous when you use our website do not sign into it or provide any information that might identify you.

Dick Smith Group requires individuals to provide accurate, up-to-date and complete personal information at the time it is collected.

## 4\. What does Dick Smith Group do with your personal information?

In addition to any purpose notified to you at the time of collection Dick Smith Group uses your personal information for the purposes of:

  * providing our services to you;
  * our internal management needs;
  * our marketing activities;
  * responding to any inquiries or comments that you submit to us;
  * any other purpose you have consented to; and
  * any use which is required or authorised by law.

## 5\. Disclosure of personal information

Dick Smith Group may disclose your personal information:

  * to third-parties we ordinarily engage for the above purposes;
  * any person or entity to whom you have consented to Dick Smith Group disclosing your personal information to; and
  * any person or entity to whom we are required or authorised to disclose your personal information to in accordance with the law
  * related bodies corporate of the Dick Smith Group

## 6\. Access and Management

You may request access to your personal information in our customer account database, or seek correction of it, by contacting our customer service team. See section 8: Contact information.

Dick Smith Group may charge a reasonable fee that is not excessive to cover the charges of retrieving your personal information from our customer account database. Dick Smith Group will not charge you for making the request.

If you believe that Dick Smith Group holds personal information about you in our customer account database that is not accurate, complete, up-to-date, relevant or information that is misleading then you may request its amendment and Dick Smith Group will respond to your request within a reasonable time. Dick Smith Group will not charge you for correcting your personal information. 

If Dick Smith Group no longer needs your personal information for any the purposes set out in this policy, or as otherwise required by law, Dick Smith Group will take such steps as are reasonable in the circumstances to destroy the information or to de-identify it.

Dick Smith Group will take reasonable steps to protect the personal information it holds from misuse, interference and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

## 7\. Opting Out / Unsubscribe

At any time you may opt out of receiving marketing communications from us. Unless you opt out, your consent to receive direct marketing communications from us and to the handling of your personal information as detailed above, will continue. Each of our marketing emails will have an unsubscribe function which will allow you to unsubscribe from all future marketing communications. All of our marketing SMS messages will also contain an unsubscribe feature. Outside of these channels, you can opt out from receiving marketing communications at any time by emailing [commercial@dicksmith.co.nz](mailto:%20commercial@dicksmith.co.nz).

## 8\. Cross-border disclosure

Dick Smith Group may disclose your personal information to recipients overseas (including in the Philippines, Hong Kong and New Zealand) to assist Dick Smith Group in providing you with products or services.

Dick Smith Group will take such steps as are reasonable in the circumstances to ensure that the information that is transferred to third parties located outside of Australia will not be held, used or disclosed by the recipient of the information in a manner that is inconsistent with the Australian Privacy Principles.

## 9\. Contact information

If you require further information regarding this policy or wish to make a complaint about a breach of the APPs by Dick Smith Group, please contact us at [commercial@dicksmith.co.nz](mailto:%20commercial@dicksmith.co.nz) or call us on 1300 003 425 if you are calling from within Australia or +64 9 887 6981 if you are calling from New Zealand or any other country, or send mail to: Attn: Privacy Officer, Dick Smith Group c/o Kogan.com, GPO Box 2579, Melbourne VIC 3001 Australia. Our office is located at 136 Buckhurst Street, South Melbourne, VIC 3205 Australia. A senior member of staff will review your complaint within 5 business days and respond to you in writing advising what action(s) Dick Smith Group will take as a result of your complaint.

## 10\. Dick Smith Group websites

When transmitting personal information from your computer to a Dick Smith Group website, you must keep in mind that the transmission of information over the Internet is not always completely secure or error-free. Other than liability that cannot lawfully be excluded, Dick Smith Group will not be liable in any way in relation to any breach of security or any unintended loss or disclosure of that information.

The Dick Smith Group websites ([www.dicksmith.com.au](https://www.dicksmith.com.au/) and [www.dicksmith.co.nz](https://www.dicksmith.co.nz/)) may use "cookies" to help personalise your online experience and save you time. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Dick Smith Group websites.

## 11\. Miscellaneous

Dick Smith Group reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy in whole or in part from time to time without notice and amendments will be effective immediately upon posting of the amended Privacy Policy on the Dick Smith Group websites.
